<zero:poetry xmlns:zero="http://arts.uwa.edu.au/els/zeroday" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<zero:poem title="0000">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid speaks in pages. He sees only what&apos;s visible written of him:</zero:line>
<zero:line>the difference that splits collier and collider. Black on black.</zero:line>
<zero:line>Widening rings: his days on buses, trains—he listens for want:</zero:line>
<zero:line>something better to do, a left-hand side capacity to hold.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>These make stories of everywhere headed south: </zero:line>
<zero:line>the conversation topics of Utah backpackers, whether they&apos;re </zero:line>
<zero:line>nameplated, contrast shifted to magpie black and white;</zero:line>
<zero:line>pinafores hovered on newsstands stacked with watchtowers</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>(blue square logo so up to the minute),</zero:line>
<zero:line>and the ones he likes—saffron &amp; galangal pink, he gets them</zero:line>
<zero:line>off context: still with a smell of rose petals giving way to weed</zero:line>
<zero:line>lifted from lakebeds, digested by swans. </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid&apos;s heard them (Hare Rama) in the city&apos;s interstices and to no one</zero:line>
<zero:line>in particular under this particular swamp cypress: odd for a conifer:</zero:line>
<zero:line>forked up its trunk and a tiger iron pedicure: planted for AC Bhaktivedanta—</zero:line>
<zero:line>become time; his step fossils in red &amp; gold stone.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid likes the percussion and its goddesses: less stolen bone</zero:line>
<zero:line>than one or another temperature of breath blown fast or slow.</zero:line>
<zero:line>Appeal and heal are one thing between here and the river: </zero:line>
<zero:line>the ones that bug him most thinking in clay: his twisted</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>or their perception sounds like an off concept of perfection</zero:line>
<zero:line>—a wishing in mirrors for miracles.</zero:line>
<zero:line>Reflection illumines the recruiter, he thinks,</zero:line>
<zero:line>and wonders whether vampires can be seen in selfies.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="0001">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid dreams of the sea—blank and grey off a coast where Graham</zero:line>
<zero:line>sounds like gram not gramme—the waves in his ears a dubplate of white</zero:line>
<zero:line>noise and exclusive-or. He dreams the wrong kind of seagull:</zero:line>
<zero:line>silver Croicocephalus, red feet and a voice of ring modulated</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>wanting. The gull fumbles through systems of casting-off:</zero:line>
<zero:line>basking shark mouthed bins hidden in drifts of seaweed;</zero:line>
<zero:line>leafless spiral bindings—shreds of half circle perforation</zero:line>
<zero:line>remaindered in the helix; wad of unmoored sticky notes.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Other gulls clustered between crests; how they whorl</zero:line>
<zero:line>the water under downdraft, make their own overtone</zero:line>
<zero:line>transverse to the surface. It occurs at the limits of system thinking—</zero:line>
<zero:line>between synapse, gyre, reflection, deviations of wave reduced to noise</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>and maybe subatomic possibilities exist somewhere else</zero:line>
<zero:line>but, whatever, nobody knows and the kid suspects the theorists</zero:line>
<zero:line>clink vodka shots with knowledge it&apos;s beyond observation</zero:line>
<zero:line>so there&apos;s nothing to lose, no quantum suicides in the papers;</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="0010">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>a list of inexplicable—why Steep Hills of Vicodin Tears</zero:line>
<zero:line>gets stars on its shoulders; why a poem—collision of astrophysics</zero:line>
<zero:line>and distance—gets its distribution; who can rock the dude-</zero:line>
<zero:line>with-pood look down the park; who can&apos;t and decants.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Back to that question of coalminer and CERN. Serve eggs boson</zero:line>
<zero:line>for breakfast all you like, you can&apos;t quark pools faster than light;</zero:line>
<zero:line>the clock&apos;s wrong somewhere between Switzerland and Italy. There&apos;s a story</zero:line>
<zero:line>in that north: true or magnetic, believing blind—fewer or less are buying it;</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>in the dream the man speaks in a coat (either black or white)</zero:line>
<zero:line>in black and white—the kid can&apos;t catch the crest of wave function collapse;</zero:line>
<zero:line>the cat in the box long-haired or short, coal or magnesium salt:</zero:line>
<zero:line>a difference between crow and gull—white eyes either way</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>so colour's all the same in the end—who do we kid</zero:line>
<zero:line>with questions of lemma &amp; toyota corollary?</zero:line>
<zero:line>a serious car, the coronary, and will it get bogged if seeing</zero:line>
<zero:line>isn't believing, if a road&apos;s only narrow bridges and cold shoulders?</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>cars for the shifting of I think, a white environment for ideas.</zero:line>
<zero:line>how warm they remain—when they call the movers and why—</zero:line>
<zero:line>there's no stroking the kitten with isotope and poison pill</zero:line>
<zero:line>but its story&apos;s bound; same goes for dogs, gods, supermassive black holes.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>A mirror&apos;s glass on one side of silver: it&apos;s EMR whoever&apos;s cut</zero:line>
<zero:line>and it gives itself the same to retina, CCD, photo-chemical filament:</zero:line>
<zero:line>the difference between diffraction and pigment doesn&apos;t result</zero:line>
<zero:line>in non-peacock, or something other than fairy wren. </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="0011">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid isn&apos;t sure if this story ever happened—remembers the street</zero:line>
<zero:line>and the two dollar shop he worked in; his mum says this all happened</zero:line>
<zero:line>and he thinks of the people he sees there: small package</zero:line>
<zero:line>of man with a face that places him from everywhere: Japan, Mexico,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Whadjuk Country; he camps by bus stops camouflaged in silver streaked beard, </zero:line>
<zero:line>heaped cloth on box after box of belongings. The kid wonders how this comma</zero:line>
<zero:line>of bone and hair gets his cardboard parlour from block to block and what the other</zero:line>
<zero:line>man says under his breath: hard shell headphones (he guesses) keep unbidden</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>orators out (somewhat) and the kid thinks it&apos;s odd that at volume he&apos;s</zero:line>
<zero:line>incomprehensible; passed close once, heard his history in eighties Australian politics:</zero:line>
<zero:line>Hawke, Bond, Rothwells all pinned under his breath. The one he called</zero:line>
<zero:line>street preacher: volume better but never enough for traffic, for weekdays,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>for strength of character or the gravelly skin white on his fingers. Correlation (inverse</zero:line>
<zero:line>or otherwise) of volume and grammar never a question with the one he called</zero:line>
<zero:line>dervish: silence and seasons always the same: beachwear at his ankles, fleece cowl;</zero:line>
<zero:line>always walking, walking. The kid&apos;s never seen these men swipe a slab of black glass—</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>or the woman with pigeons in cat carriers—the kid thinks it&apos;s a different</zero:line>
<zero:line>map that way, pictures the transition between Mercator and its transverse:</zero:line>
<zero:line>the moment the earth takes curvature: how it&apos;s hidden until the fresh coat</zero:line>
<zero:line>of satellite tiles, hidden from these sleeping on asphalt and powerless battery.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>That street, it&apos;s this he remembers: right leg bent and his sole against layers</zero:line>
<zero:line>of paste, paint, poster paper: Rizla and Drum keep cost in inverse</zero:line>
<zero:line>proportion to dopamine; a vague twist of off-white Nikes and the old</zero:line>
<zero:line>lady&apos;s shoulder drops; she pitches left and half steps to stay up;</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>and after the kid&apos;s steps are ouroboric, tail-recursive; cycle of contact</zero:line>
<zero:line>and non- and at speed the kid doesn&apos;t see the slate grey patter</zero:line>
<zero:line>of chewing gum and shoe dust, the black savannah on his left shoulder.</zero:line>
<zero:line>He passes cheap sushi and unbelievable deals on overseas calls, spears right</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>into the black valley of margin vs volume: mannequins wrapped in tapped aquifer</zero:line>
<zero:line>and public sculpture doubles as seating, k-grind, and however the kid thinks back now:</zero:line>
<zero:line>the red sea press of oxygen breaching his bloodstream; a half-baked kind of elevation</zero:line>
<zero:line>on herringbone slabs; weird hearing cliché in his voice and no response:</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>from fear, IFF failure, or slow cognition of shoppers he never found out,</zero:line>
<zero:line>left instead with the differing moments of other men  and a crazed relationship with theft:</zero:line>
<zero:line>wonders about birritt  under blacktop: who holds story and the oxidation states of iron:</zero:line>
<zero:line>its shift from red to black with gash, pavement, hours. Not today, though,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>he flows under bridges as if split between aquine and equine, horse and water,</zero:line>
<zero:line>assemblage of legs and surface tension. Altogether, the kid didn&apos;t see more</zero:line>
<zero:line>than half a mouth fixed open, wide eye and blonde shock raked across gravity;</zero:line>
<zero:line>didn&apos;t cinch the distance and only stopped to pick up dropped belongings.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks perhaps it happened: his mum has a story: an Instagram</zero:line>
<zero:line>screenshot—He just fuckin chased a dude who stole a woman&apos;s bag —that phone long gone</zero:line>
<zero:line>to wherever phones go (mythical land of bromide, Li-ion, cadmium) </zero:line>
<zero:line>and the image silted under years, lost amongst some quadrillion pixels.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:hidden_poem title="0011">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>the kid dreams of himself and a sister: her face the same</zero:line>
<zero:line>as an elfin actress whose name he won&apos;t remember when he wakes</zero:line>
<zero:line>and their connection label-deep. She&apos;s thin, red teeth and white</zero:line>
<zero:line>fabric at her hip shifts under his touch, retakes its place like satin</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>but he sees an off angle in its bias—streak of grey from hip to hem</zero:line>
<zero:line>and he&apos;s headed away with his dad (a face made from scratch)</zero:line>
<zero:line>while the room is packed and late day sunlight </zero:line>
<zero:line>woodgrains voices, talk about new books: plotlines just beyond </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>his capacity to maintain faith or a background in physics—moments</zero:line>
<zero:line>of force a mystery, let alone general relativity; doesn&apos;t know the kind of tree </zero:line>
<zero:line>let alone the episode of brother-shovel bludgeoning. </zero:line>
<zero:line>In amongst this the kid hears his mother&apos;s voice, </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>turns past the vase of regret-me-nots. The late day sunlight&apos;s</zero:line>
<zero:line>backward: it has mass and no momentum;</zero:line>
<zero:line>his mother left there in its yellowing, faced away palms flat at the table</zero:line>
<zero:line>and her hair&apos;s dark horizon, a width of sunset above muslin—</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>white cloth stretched now on hollow bones</zero:line>
<zero:line>and turned on her left ankle; the kid left to wonder if the right</zero:line>
<zero:line>foot&apos;s missing, and when she rests on top of the wind the left tucks</zero:line>
<zero:line>under and he hears the squall in her voice: descent and modulation.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:hidden_poem>

<zero:poem title="0100">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>And In times of plague, it is forbidden to spit at cats whatever condition their hip,</zero:line>
<zero:line>but what happens when the kid thinks of his mum? love must propagate</zero:line>
<zero:line>at greater than 300,000 ks a second; otherwise the guy riding the c train,</zero:line>
<zero:line>he lobs an orange forward and his wife&apos;s forbidden to think of him.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Dreams of dad and sister—superposition of stranger and familiar:</zero:line>
<zero:line>the kid wonders why seagulls sound different in movies: Hitchcock&apos;s</zero:line>
<zero:line>made of mixtur-trautonium; cries wheeled through wide arcs on</zero:line>
<zero:line>European updrafts, far from the kid&apos;s winterless city: too lost to feel at home</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>and maybe the city fishes for a kind of hydrophobic Moses—fogs its breath</zero:line>
<zero:line>between concrete and glass mangroves, rifles mounds of red check</zero:line>
<zero:line>blanket, stacked plastic takeaway containers—comes bucket hatted,</zero:line>
<zero:line>lectures twentieth century politics under its breath</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>by the Tiergarten-twinned crier. The kid thinks, or will, is this his real dad</zero:line>
<zero:line>while asleep; what it means to kiss his dream-sister and where love goes</zero:line>
<zero:line>when the recipient&apos;s fictional—out to clouds over oceans,</zero:line>
<zero:line>its vector stripped of direction.  The kid feels his skin ruffled,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>pushed in a fresh gust of moments he feels the hair on his limbs</zero:line>
<zero:line>as a weight of white fabric, the temperature drop in evening air.</zero:line>
<zero:line>He knows now how to hold this eigenvalue of affection;</zero:line>
<zero:line>scale asphalt streams and remember waking.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="0101">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The <span class="meme">kid</span> pictures what these streets feel before his time—</zero:line>
<zero:line>hard plastic buckets passed for seats at school, the kid&apos;s history</zero:line>
<zero:line>teacher&apos;s laugh once (4G sluggish through old ferroconcrete):</zero:line>
<zero:line>her day: a beige handset to talk and a meeting took days to affect—</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>streets shorn: his diminished ability for lostness, history wikiform now</zero:line>
<zero:line>and friends&apos; everpresence: a cognition of <span class="meme">whatever this font is</span> and felines.</zero:line>
<zero:line>The kid thinks what colour a fairy wren would be without the screen</zero:line>
<zero:line>of code division multiple access sheened over light poles—</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>a blue, he thinks, as if it&apos;s raven to asphalt: a brighter, higher saturation</zero:line>
<zero:line>black—the kids here&apos;d scavenge colour from wheelie bins, jacaranda</zero:line>
<zero:line>flowers and motor oil rainbows in first rains; run fingers</zero:line>
<zero:line>in the wind to listen at beige painted front doors, all the streets&apos; numbers</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>in stainless steel, oxide blemished at their edges: digits curled in heat and blanched</zero:line>
<zero:line>under a crust of salt and old age. Stall all the nodes, the kid calls to himself: </zero:line>
<zero:line>calls for silence in a forest of squat altars to the union of fibreoptic and copper,</zero:line>
<zero:line>where an easterly yellows lawn and shed computer carapace sounds the sea,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>tide line littered with toner shells, OLED boxes, IKEA beast&apos;s withered bones.</zero:line>
<zero:line>Beachcombers come in vans with blank black rimmed eyes; creatures</zero:line>
<zero:line>peer out beneath the clay tile breakers and galvanised waves—</zero:line>
<zero:line>give them the welcome you&apos;d get for spoonbenders at funerals;</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>brighter than you&apos;d think where sun doesn&apos;t reach</zero:line>
<zero:line>and seasons wash over unnoticed: spring, winter, <em>The West Wing</em>,</zero:line>
<zero:line>and always bled through the edge of metaphor, these seagulls.</zero:line>
<zero:line>The kid tries to think where he&apos;s seen them; hasn&apos;t been to the beach.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="0110">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks of the river, the stretch where it lies back; no rush to the ocean,</zero:line>
<zero:line>thinks where the line lies between river and sea: possibly salt or where the gulls won&apos;t go;</zero:line>
<zero:line>they beg for fish &amp; chips the same either way and water&apos;s equally clear</zero:line>
<zero:line>upstream where potatoes begin their flow, take measure of rain, river;</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>let salt and vinegar follow where seagulls and grease traps meet </zero:line>
<zero:line>in the neverending car wreck of canola, revenant forest burned below decks</zero:line>
<zero:line>and the kid thinks if it&apos;s always been there for seeing—that fish &amp; chips</zero:line>
<zero:line>come from somewhere other than the shopfront and Mediterranean name,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>(and what&apos;s Mediterranean anyway but a Tolkienesque way of saying</zero:line>
<zero:line>the whole radiates from here), and what if it doesn&apos;t belong in a place</zero:line>
<zero:line>where the topsoil&apos;s as thin as silence, a collection of yesterdays struggling</zero:line>
<zero:line>for sunlight like a family of cats in a box (white cats more often deaf).  </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid&apos;s been on the end of that anger: split lip and an hour late to school,</zero:line>
<zero:line>hidden in a rosemary hedge; started to think (now he&apos;s been dragged over doorways</zero:line>
<zero:line>for locked-on muscles down his left, as if drunk or overdone witchcraft)</zero:line>
<zero:line>that unvoiced stories make for collapsed wave functions: dead futures</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>for ghosts of yesterdays: the Erwin Schrödinger thing shows that cats sat in boxes</zero:line>
<zero:line>long before <span class="meme">can has</span>, perhaps that only—the kid thinks of the ethics, then, of observation:</zero:line>
<zero:line>how much to insure against wave function collapse, the end of a present, </zero:line>
<zero:line>what the actuaries can check—the actual fuck—whether there&apos;s claim for act of god.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="0111">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid knows now it&apos;s no lowland holiday: this language moved from his head</zero:line>
<zero:line>to his hand; remembers it small and coiled in his prefrontal cortex</zero:line>
<zero:line>—or that&apos;s how it felt—tight behind his eyes and pressed against slow bone.</zero:line>
<zero:line>language would pine for outside, backlit plane where mechanics are frictionless.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>He starts to see (language in his hand now) which machine he&apos;d shaped:</zero:line>
<zero:line>used to think of his CPU, an aluminium and silicon millipede needed obedience</zero:line>
<zero:line>training—he&apos;d bark in unspoken tongues with no word for consequence or pocketful</zero:line>
<zero:line>of treats. And it&apos;s him, he sees, that salivates at the sound of exclusive or </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>and begun to see in algorithm, the city in VLSI: A* finds the fastest path</zero:line>
<zero:line>from screen to biological imperative, each street&apos;s a switching code</zero:line>
<zero:line>for whichever function he needs—north bridge for pictures, memory;</zero:line>
<zero:line>south for outside—the kid keeps cyclomatic complexity low, never crosses routes;</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>never mixes strips of asphalt. Today he takes his fifty-sixth route on the left, the path</zero:line>
<zero:line>to Pasquale&apos;s: treads with care at the driveway: he&apos;s down to seventeen nanometres</zero:line>
<zero:line>between routes out of the house; a miniscule slip could pitch him hours south and east:</zero:line>
<zero:line>once there he&apos;s carnelian and Carnaby&apos;s: red tail trail cakes his shoes and won&apos;t shake loose.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Steps slow, the kid inches out and thinks his friend&apos;s handle: picked for a favourite way in:</zero:line>
<zero:line>some say ess-cue-ell-eye, others sequel-eye. The friend says he&apos;s a storm&apos;s eye, likes it squally.</zero:line>
<zero:line>pasqli squats on a cheap office chair—backrest sneezes brominated foam</zero:line>
<zero:line>and doesn&apos;t lift from minimum position—quizzes code wired and never asks one question</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>at once. pasqli's grin spins counter-clockwise within his cardioid pattern of silver wrappings—</zero:line>
<zero:line>pop tart pupae; Nicorette foil. The kid asks a new path: tells pasqli he&apos;d walked the causeway</zero:line>
<zero:line>25-1 exits west of the track that took him to school (kept open and unused), the road</zero:line>
<zero:line>over artificial anabranch—long land filled and given back to the river: a garbage Manhattan.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Sunk in sheoak needles, sun dipped beneath the treeline, the kid clapped at mosquitos in air</zero:line>
<zero:line>grey with ground out wattle bird conversation: djiti-djiti visible but overpowered. shoes</zero:line>
<zero:line>on blue aggregate, chin on his shoulder, he checked back on his path and she&apos;d stood</zero:line>
<zero:line>with her hand at his elbow, wolf in blue ink springing from her wrist. —these </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>were called condil, you understand why they gather—who—you hear them speak</zero:line>
<zero:line>their necks red—them—yes. that language, listen, has words for hearing—i—listen</zero:line>
<zero:line>louder—will say what you&apos;ve forgotten—.  pasqli ticks in his yellow foam halo.  —got</zero:line>
<zero:line>your laptop—yep—ok—. checks the pockets in his coat of mathematics: power</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>and modulo, folded tickets of hops through city block ciphers. sixteen languages</zero:line>
<zero:line>between pasqli&apos;s keys and the city&apos;s systems; two need speaking. pasqli works blind:</zero:line>
<zero:line>trades voltage for time; says tell me about trees and escape' where one equals zero;</zero:line>
<zero:line>sleep(5); black enter clicks and pasqli&apos;s watch—grids mocked in monospace</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>freeze from black and the shapes of plan, order, approval—filings for a fresh centimetre;</zero:line>
<zero:line>new nand gates for navigation: the blue wolf&apos;s house, hand at his elbow. The kid&apos;s route home</zero:line>
<zero:line>stays the same as always: left where the white terrier warns against trespass, he steps</zero:line>
<zero:line>on pavers&apos; hard right. This stretch crosses the path to his mum&apos;s and he stops:</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>the kid&apos;s wish to be wavelike; to cross concrete at odds with his system: a knowing</zero:line>
<zero:line>how many nanometres between here and awake. The kid turns into his street,</zero:line>
<zero:line>between boxes he sees one edge of the city—tower glass slate in sundown light.</zero:line>
<zero:line>The man in tangerine to ankle and wrist folds away pedestrians watch your step, stripes</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>fine the light from seams on his uniform, from traffic cones&apos; chords, galvanised</zero:line>
<zero:line>in black counters on the a-frame folded, placed back in the aluminium tray, pale grey flat</zero:line>
<zero:line>in low-pressure sodium light. The kid steps across his body to set feet in line—</zero:line>
<zero:line>each millimetre either side keeps its own logic—steps sideways at his gate to stay on thread. </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1000">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid begins again—what if this grounding weren&apos;t given an overlay,</zero:line>
<zero:line>but how sad is land shorn of narrative; thinks for new kinds of finding:</zero:line>
<zero:line>song for CDMA, ley for TCP and voice for satmap tile—</zero:line>
<zero:line>they replace heat haze and air (always absent on a Google map);</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>the kid isn&apos;t sure how boundaries of federation and old war</zero:line>
<zero:line>will show, isn&apos;t convinced it&apos;ll matter: everyone hunts in Venn diagrams</zero:line>
<zero:line>anyway: the courier, kookaburra, cat; thinks it odd what comes from the cloud</zero:line>
<zero:line>has stiff edges and thinks of overlaid ghosts—political map and Gondwanaland,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>and anyway there&apos;s an end to what happens when maps run down scale ratios—</zero:line>
<zero:line>the story has cartography compost under its referent and maybe the paper</zero:line>
<zero:line>these days is all Scalable Vector or wavelet compression—one-to-one sugar gums</zero:line>
<zero:line>as old as the colony and still too small for story. Pinch for big picture.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks at the deckled edge of space—if coastlines approach infinite distance </zero:line>
<zero:line>where borders skirt sand grains and when: paint blue if its submerging&apos;s permanent;</zero:line>
<zero:line>beige for solid sand at any tide—no thinks the kid, a map has to have scales for distance,</zero:line>
<zero:line>viscosity; for a sense of wetness at the back of a hand and pasts without written language</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>or colour code; imagines schematics for GIS: fear for getting lost, for missed</zero:line>
<zero:line>plans; anything else a kind of wrong-scale proprioception, orientation &amp; origin</zero:line>
<zero:line>when nothing&apos;s cartesian—centres are everywhere and this, the kid thinks,</zero:line>
<zero:line>is a way to greet a friend in the ground, to disinter on an older timescale.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1001">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Satmap mosaic has red tracks; never cold days and rain to wash clay pale</zero:line>
<zero:line>back into winter for coat after coat: old wood eaten from its middle </zero:line>
<zero:line>and nailed labels into stone—the line splits dolerite from granite,</zero:line>
<zero:line>one grey pixel from the next in UTM projection and however many million years.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks of equivalent time scales: his mum&apos;s shown him the books</zero:line>
<zero:line>in old newsagents (stately logo from the eighties), told him of her mum </zero:line>
<zero:line>and a perfect bound perception of the city: UBD always missing new streets,</zero:line>
<zero:line>clear vinyl case lost in a floor well and white string adrift on its spine.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks of equivalent time scales: three days with screen splinters, </zero:line>
<zero:line>no credit, SOS Only—a list of conditions he striates time with, some pushed</zero:line>
<zero:line>into the page: his walking transient to analogue: slices of time from which he overlooks</zero:line>
<zero:line>whatever comes before; this is his angle of incidence.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks of equivalent time scales, old folks&apos; homes:</zero:line>
<zero:line>big doors for furniture, for passing; hollow bones and frictionless hinges;</zero:line>
<zero:line>doors to fit tomorrows where the kid&apos;s this is rose-tinted and Zimmer assisted:</zero:line>
<zero:line>golden age for climate action, everyone fed and respected.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>He thinks of a square on a calendar somewhere, as yet unprinted, unexed,</zero:line>
<zero:line>a fix for his broken proprioception, the set of accelerometers</zero:line>
<zero:line>embedded or wedged in his pocket. The kid thinks the trade isn&apos;t zero sum</zero:line>
<zero:line>(or even close) but won&apos;t know the cost until its deduction.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1010">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid considers whichever face in the mirror as if he&apos;s some kind</zero:line>
<zero:line>of slightly different future; red eyed like a box-sealed seagull:</zero:line>
<zero:line>isotope, poison gas, concentric shells of observation and his wave</zero:line>
<zero:line>function slowly collapsed between there and somewhere zero distance away;</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>half the face more relaxed on an axis, more relaxed than it ought to be </zero:line>
<zero:line>anyway, and to rinse the face and return to bed  would be a comfort to think except</zero:line>
<zero:line>that&apos;s how it starts: to lose a self in the looking, walk without maps</zero:line>
<zero:line>and there&apos;s always accounting where mothers are involved.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks his species of lost has a different name:</zero:line>
<zero:line>turns his face as if its shape&apos;s the same and elevation&apos;s changed</zero:line>
<zero:line>or a short war&apos;s drawn a line of foreign politics; perhaps a long one;</zero:line>
<zero:line>the kid brings his lips back against his teeth and breathes through force:</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>a spread of stubbled topsoil and the wrong side myoclonic in reflection. </zero:line>
<zero:line>He shuts his eyes and feels like a chart of pandemic spread with a zero</zero:line>
<zero:line>height y axis: origin everywhere and all the nations&apos; names overlaid,</zero:line>
<zero:line>pinched until the city&apos;s the size of a pixel: the right green and dry, left all at sea.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1011">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid thinks of the day he saw his mum at the demo—his girlfriend had </zero:line>
<zero:line>taken him—the kid thinks this is the day he&apos;d drawn a winter oak</zero:line>
<zero:line>high on her thigh, his mum had found its mirror in black leatherette</zero:line>
<zero:line>against their dining table, wondered if it were a sign and of what,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>it'd sat that way all night and nobody touched it, his girlfriend emerged</zero:line>
<zero:line>in cold morning sun; tree-drawn and sleep-ruffled. His mum could never guess</zero:line>
<zero:line>what pencil made the branches and their echo, both the colour of ghost.</zero:line>
<zero:line>The kid no longer remembers, guesses this memory is in the house</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>that looked over a floodplain: samphire flared red every May with the heavy</zero:line>
<zero:line>smell of sunk—the kid could never resist the white crystalline trails, crusted</zero:line>
<zero:line>before footfall as if to say the place was solid, safe, and a mass of black streaks</zero:line>
<zero:line>where he&apos;d left his balance. The kid thinks it&apos;s that house, that morning—a smell</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>connects the house and its garage, a sound of seagull calls. Except the kid finds the sound</zero:line>
<zero:line>slippery in his mind, remembered or manufactured he isn&apos;t clear, called from across the blue</zero:line>
<zero:line>line where the people of dream still skirmish with old conquerors, and the kid thinks</zero:line>
<zero:line>perhaps that house was too far upstream; all water fowl, or rainbow bee-eater on good days,</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>the path down to flats coincident with concrete columns, cardboard placards: primary</zero:line>
<zero:line>colours fuzzed at their edges. The kid remembers backs, asphalt between however</zero:line>
<zero:line>many feet; a still image before blinking—mouth open in profile, eyes angled upward</zero:line>
<zero:line>at free air and bedsheet banner. A still image before walking forward—</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>the kid isn&apos;t sure how many colours he&apos;d used for the koi tail he sprayed</zero:line>
<zero:line>on the cops&apos; car: he counts out in his head: five shades in its spots (not counting white)</zero:line>
<zero:line>alone and wonders how he&apos;d had that many cans. Tags on the buildings simpler, </zero:line>
<zero:line>black and he feels a twinge for the bricks&apos; biscuit surface—the colour of thigh-branch. </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>There&apos;s the day the kid asked what the crowd were angry about: a shoeprint solidity</zero:line>
<zero:line>in details listed from memory: forest green cotton in cylinders ending a woman&apos;s dreads;</zero:line>
<zero:line>her face and its terrain—fault and topography. The kid remembers all kinds of acrylic on card:</zero:line>
<zero:line>climate strike, black lives, can&apos;t place what the placards said that day, and no-one remembers</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>the police car&apos;s koi panels, his girlfriend&apos;s tattoo jet black fresh on her scapula: oxbow curve</zero:line>
<zero:line>and Möbius topology of a narrow-headed snake; measure of venom in its tail; no-one</zero:line>
<zero:line>remembers a spray-can bandolier—the day&apos;s thread pulled loose from its selvedge and shifts</zero:line>
<zero:line>in crosshatch across memory: the different pitch of before and after; yesterday&apos;s moiré. </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1100">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>Maybe AC gets it on the moors, AC on the edge of desert. Both ways</zero:line>
<zero:line>are ok as long as the kid thinks in irreducible difference: one and zero:</zero:line>
<zero:line>AC&apos;s plague the sickness from within: rats under asphalt, flowers under </zero:line>
<zero:line>ice pools&apos; thaw: Law and the other AC lacking a Brontëoid immunity, a serum</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>against anything shifting at greater than 300 thousand ks a second.</zero:line>
<zero:line>No such thing, but there&apos;s always meth, fluoxetine, eight hour days, TV;</zero:line>
<zero:line>left to wonder which AC is coolest: Bhaktivedanta, Carson, or Camus.</zero:line>
<zero:line>Could even be Chekov, Clarke, that Crowley nut; but Carter always a fave:</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>so much blood, so much blue hair. Nobody knew substitutes for love</zero:line>
<zero:line>better than that character—his little key, her giveaway. No privileged upbringing, </zero:line>
<zero:line>the kid thinks of someone he&apos;s seen on the streets: thonged and hood open</zero:line>
<zero:line>to asphalt, how he walks unseen between beat cops and geek orthodox priests:  </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>his different occupation of space: face made of machine learning:</zero:line>
<zero:line>neuron and loss function. A recombinant net retrodicting an alien landscape,</zero:line>
<zero:line>that one finds a way through space with a map of nowhere except where he is,</zero:line>
<zero:line>where he treads on a dead sea of electromagnetism: concrete footpaths </zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>laid long form and bevelled, seamed to seem as slabs; pavers cast upside</zero:line>
<zero:line>down and aggregate sunk blue to pale faces. The kid&apos;s seen office workers</zero:line>
<zero:line>on the same pavers: shoulders around their jowls and the jealous glares</zero:line>
<zero:line>at the passerines in street trees: wattle birds, lorikeets, the habitats of Carnaby&apos;s:</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1101">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>there&apos;s—land as manifold. The kid doesn&apos;t think this, what kind of colour infills</zero:line>
<zero:line>a frame; how it&apos;s numbered: Pantone or hexadecimal (CMYK, RGB, HSB)</zero:line>
<zero:line>anyway not the same as satmap or world political Mercator, street map, postage</zero:line>
<zero:line>stamp. The manifold asks where here is, and when: how wide is scale, a count of terms</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>and how we come to them, recoded colour over time: redshifted leaves under plane</zero:line>
<zero:line>trees, swamp cypress, and how long it takes ex-Soviet nations to flower. And that&apos;s where</zero:line>
<zero:line>the kid thinks: in how wide-voiced the chord of sunflower, oak, Crimea. A shift</zero:line>
<zero:line>of perception in cycles of twenty-four, three-hundred-sixty-five, ten; how to address</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>that memory on the network—forget the machine and let the machine forget: the kid&apos;s</zero:line>
<zero:line>brain as cache and conduit for what&apos;s in the cloud and a map of bigger things:</zero:line>
<zero:line>a catalogue of places outside existence. The kid wonders if the seagulls make the same</zero:line>
<zero:line>sound between ticks of the clock when states&apos; borders change, when magnetic north drifts</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>on its figure of eight and twists the map—fingers down and a flex of tendon.</zero:line>
<zero:line>If there&apos;s a lesser modulation on their breath without sunlight: those black fantails:</zero:line>
<zero:line>the kid gets why they&apos;re called djiti-djiti but only in daylight; the song from the box</zero:line>
<zero:line>trees on black streets needs another name, a name that takes longer to say at solstice.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1110">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid never obsessed for mathematics: thinks of it as language where everything&apos;s</zero:line>
<zero:line>indefinite pronoun: its blades shear away names, everything from the kid&apos;s to Latin binomial,</zero:line>
<zero:line>instead got his physics from wood and bearing: shuv and kickflip for medial axis theorem,</zero:line>
<zero:line>his one hundred eighty times table; how numbers&apos; mass irons the lines from space.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>No longer ok on uneven terrain, the kid&apos;s given up on old quarries—cuts flushed</zero:line>
<zero:line>with oxidation states of iron: red and black splitting grevillea thickets as sun dews</zero:line>
<zero:line>on the city quilted below. Once, an odd white light on the horizon line: sun-bright,</zero:line>
<zero:line>rain and dust a rug shaken out between the kid and it; a warp of not knowing reflected</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>sun from artificial: an Airbus beneath him, a swim in black and red cuts in stone:</zero:line>
<zero:line>once somebody&apos;s job and sprayed over with postcodes: 6108, 6071, 6003. Another way</zero:line>
<zero:line>to quantise country, to grid the granite—a good year it pulses green to black: subpixel</zero:line>
<zero:line>that winks out feeding lichen, sundew, grevillea and New Holland Honeyeater; the whole</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>thing: a loss of productivity. Back then, in the hills, the kid couldn&apos;t figure out the lines of it,</zero:line>
<zero:line>its striation—how that white light might look from a parallax angle and how straight</zero:line>
<zero:line>the 33kVs from flown overhead, missing the misdirection of topography. Reduced</zero:line>
<zero:line>to powers of two: Mersenne primes, perfect numbers, how to use them.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>

<zero:poem title="1111">
<zero:stanza>
<zero:line>The kid wonders how far he pokes out into rivers of future, past—thinks of a self</zero:line>
<zero:line>as swamp cypress, knees on their banks, a line with odd polyrhythm and this his ascender</zero:line>
<zero:line>of grounding; one side of posture locked on, and everything reddens before a fall.</zero:line>
</zero:stanza>
</zero:poem>
</zero:poetry>